NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office Files. 6174/011
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Misc. Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  Letters from candidates for Ulster County legislature, seeking endorsement from Hudson Valley Labor Council or Hudson Valley Council of Carpenters; letter to Sen. Al D'Amato from president of Upper Hudson Valley Labor Council, decrying filibuster of president's $16 billion stimulus package, April 19, 1993; resolution in support of SEIU Justice for Janitors Campaign; flyer by SEIU re IBM outsourcing janitorial services to non-union contractor Environmental Consultants; flyer and letter re Central Labor Council (Schenectady) Labor Day parade, August 4, 1989; invitation and flyer from Rep. Matt McHugh re conference, "AIDS: A Challenge for the '90s," October 2, 1989; decision and order in Article 78 proceeding by bidder Anjac Enterprises against Westchester County, re low-bid dispute, January 31, 1989; executive order by Westchester county executive, adding clause to construction contracts that failure to pay prevailing wage by contractors or subcontractors would constitute breach of contract and be grounds for denial of award, October 28, 1988; newsletter by Hudson Valley Greenway Council, July 1989
- UHVLC Minutes, 1988-1993 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  Minutes of Upper Hudson Valley Labor Council
- Hudson Valley Area Labor Council, 1995-1996 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  Constitution; minutes; correspondence
- UHLVC Meetings, 1990-1992 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  Advertising rate flyer for the Daily Freeman, Kingston, effective May 1, 1990; design and rate quote for bumper sticker for Upper Hudson Valley Labor Council, with copy of check to Stacey Publishing, October 29, 1990; AFL-CIO approved vendor list; letter from U.S. Department of Labor, offering video, "Completing Your LM-3," re required filing, October 5, 1990; meeting notice for NYS AFL-CIO political endorsements
- ABC Awards and Printing, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  Flyer and brochure by Eastern New York Occupational and Environmental Health Center; minutes of Upper Hudson Area Central Labor Council; financial report for April 1997; minutes of Presidents Statewide CLC meeting; Model Cities Survey and Application Form, with cover letter from AFL-CIO; NYS AFL-CIO report on plant closings and layoffs, April 30, 1997; NYS AFL-CIO memoranda opposing or supporting proposed state legislation; newsletter, Maritime, AFL-CIO Maritime Trades Department, criticizing NAFTA, April 1997; business card for ABC Awards, Signs and Printing, Inc.; printing rate card; handwritten notes; agendas for conferences and workshops
- NYS School-To-Work Symposium, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  Flyer for contract rally, Local 131 IUE-GE, May 17; tentative agenda for NYS AFL-CIO School-to-Work Symposium, May 10; letter from Assemblyman Jacob Gunther III in support of prevailing wage, March 31; memoranda in support of proposed state legislation, from NYS AFL-CIO or NYS Building and Construction Trades Council; flyers opposing proposed federal legislation; memo re Jobs with Justice campaign, April 17; Jobs with Justice "Solidarity Notes" newsletter, highlighting problems with "workfare" program; brochure form Cornell ILR for Certificate Program in Public Sector Stewardship Training; agendas and registration forms for conferences
- NYS AFL-CIO Correspondence, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  AFL-CIO talking points/position papers on fast-track trade negotiating authority, proposed government contracting/procurement reforms, computation of consumer price index, other national issues; NYS AFL-CIO memoranda of support or opposition to proposed state legislation; newsletter, Unity, featuring cover story opposing NYS constitutional convention; NYS constitution, amended through January 1, 1996; Upper Hudson Area Labor Council minutes; list of members; poster/folded brochure, "The Road to Union City: A Guide to Greatness for Local Unions and Their AFL-CIO Labor Councils," with statement by AFL-CIO Executive Council, Union Cities Equal Strong Communities; agenda for AFL-CIO School-to-Work Symposium, with cover letter, April 21; NYS AFL-CIO Health Care Bulletin: Fact Sheet on New York Health Care Reform Act of 1996; flyer for 1997 Summer Schools for Union Women, with cover letter; flyer for Irish-American Labor Coalition: American Labor Committee for Human Rights in Northern Ireland march in St. Patrick's Day Parade in NYC; newsletter, The Builders, voice of the Building and Construction Trades Department, AFL-CIO, featuring legislative report; brochure for Labor Summer School at Cornell ILR
- Upper Hudson Valley Labor Council, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  Minutes; brochure from NYS AFL-CIO re workplace safety protections, Dole v. Dow; flyers for rally in support of food service workers at Bard College; statement by AFL-CIO Executive Council re strawberry workers march, supporting right to organize; materials re Liberty Healthcare Management Group, provider of drug and alcohol dependency services; materials re mini-grants for school-to-work projects; correspondence between Upper Hudson Valley Labor Council and NYS Labor-Religion Coalition; AFL-CIO commentary on report of the Social Security Advisory Council
- Upper Hudson Area Labor Council-Meeting 11/25/96, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  Minutes; campaign brochures for Rep. Maurice Hinchey (D), by NYS AFL-CIO; proposal for union participation in public access TV in Hudson Valley Region; material for election day, including talking points re Clinton's success, labor's role in the election, highlights of the Working Women's Vote '96 campaign, comparison of union household vote for Congress, 1980-94 (percent Republican), with cover letter to Central Labor Councils; memo to NYS AFL-CIO Executive Board from president Ed Cleary, re 1996 Election Recap, November 19; materials re changes in NAFTA Implementation Act, with cover letter from president Ed Cleary, November 20; memo from Cleary re NYS plant closings and layoff report, October 31; minutes of Columbia Greene Private Industry Council, June 15
- Upper Hudson Area Labor Council-Meeting 10/28/96, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  Minutes; Ellenville NAACP newsletter, featuring cover story, "Stop Burning Black Churches!" spring/summer 1996, and fall/winter newsletter, urging voting; newsletter from NYC Central Labor Council, noting override of Mayor Giuliani's living wage veto, September; newsletter, Jewish Labor Committee Review, fall; flyer by Town of Olive Democratic Committee for fall frankfurter festival and rally for Assembly candidate; NYS plant closings and layoff report, September; materials re union-busting tactics
- Upper Hudson Area Labor Council-Meeting 9/23/96, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  Minutes; letter re 50th anniversary dinner; handwritten notes and sign-in sheet
- CLC Meeting-7/22/96, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  Minutes; handwritten notes; letter from AFL-CIO Committee on Political Education (COPE) re kick-off meeting for 1996 political program in 26th Congressional District; press release announcing NYS AFL-CIO endorsement of Maurice Hinchey for 26th Congressional District, July 18; description of political program, April 8; memo from NYS AFL-CIO to Central Labor Councils re need for immediate response to Republican Party attacks on AFL-CIO ads re Medicare, including libel lawsuit threats against television stations, July 17; announcement brochures for Cornell Labor Studies programs; memo re key Senate votes; weekly newsletter fax, Work in Progress; Labor '96 Mission Statement and mobilization organizational chart; bound publication, "America Needs a Raise: Economics Presentation for Labor '96 Organizers"
- CLC Meeting-Correspondence and Minutes, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  June. Minutes; political action alerts and updates; fundraising letter from Rep. Maurice Hinchey; flyer for Hinchey Ulster County campaign kick-off; other candidate literature
- Upper Hudson Area Labor Council-Meeting 5/20/96, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  Minutes; Cornell ILR Extension flyer for workshop, "Unfair Labor Practice Charges: Making Your Best Case to the NLRB"; brochure for Cornell ILR 20th Annual Labor Summer School; brochure for Cornell ILR Occupational Safety and Health certificate program; brochure for Cornell ILR Labor Studies Program; flyer re AFL-CIO-sponsored organizing workshops; letter re AFL-CIO national conference for Central Labor Councils; flyer for NYS AFL-CIO conference, "Upstate Ports Deliver for New York"; cover letter; related newspaper clipping; conference call for NYS AFL-CIO 1996 Annual Legislative Conference, "America Needs a Raise," May 22; NYS AFL-CIO plant closings and layoffs report for month of April; materials for NYS Health Care Campaign; materials for Joel Tyner for State Senate campaign
- Upper Hudson Area Labor Council-Meeting 4/22/96, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  Minutes; proclamation by Ulster County for Labor History Month; letter to NYS AFL-CIO from Rep. Maurice Hinchey re various labor-related legislative issues; flyers for Union Summer; letter from NYS AFL-CIO to Central Labor Council presidents re list of U.S. Senators voting for and against an increase in the federal minimum wage, April 4; Statistical and Tactical Information Report, National Organizing Committee, AFL-CIO; agenda for Hudson Valley/Catskill Partnership and Lower Hudson Worker Education Consortium staff development conference day, "Preparing for Workforce 2000"; letter from AFL-CIO Department of Legislation re minimum wage vote in House of Representatives and Senate, April 1; letter from United Food and Commercial Workers Local 1262 to Kingston Holiday Inn, informing management that the union, previously a large account, would boycott the facility until anti-union campaign against local organizing efforts ceased, April 8; Eastern New York Occupational and Health Program Mid-Hudson Satellite Clinic Advisory Board meeting minutes, February 6; letter to Assembly Speaker Sheldon Silver from Assembly Majority Leader Michael Bragman urging restoration of the Workplace Literacy Program as a separate program rather than merge it with others into a block grant as proposed by the governor, March 20; letter from NYS AFL-CIO president Ed Cleary to president of Upper Hudson Valley Central Labor Council, re striking newspaper unions in Detroit and boycott by AFL-CIO of Gannett newspaper USA Today, April 4; similar letter from AFL-CIO president John Sweeney, March 28; news briefs from NYC Central Labor Council; newspaper clipping re prison labor
- Upper Hudson Area Labor Council-Meeting March 1996 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  Minutes; AFL-CIO Legislative Alert, re weakening of OSHA enforcement, February 26, 1996; newsletter from Ulster County School-to-Work Program; multi-page AFL-CIO fact sheet re Pat Buchanan's positions on workers' issues
- Upper Hudson Area Labor Council-Meeting, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  Feb. Minutes; printout of members of Upper Hudson Valley Labor Council
- Upper Hudson Area Labor Council-Meeting 1/22/96, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  Minutes; announcement for NYS AFL-CIO 1996 Scholarship; urgent request from AFL-CIO for "Adopt-a-Family" assistance program for striking workers, January 31; flyer for International Women's Day rally for women's rights, by Mid-Hudson National People's Campaign
- Legislative Action Committee, 1995-1996 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  AFL-CIO Legislative Action Committee Lobbying Report re status of various pieces of legislation, votes by Rep. Hinchey, March 26, 1996; talking points for meetings with key Democrats re budget negotiations; briefing papers, "Why We Say Republicans Voted to Shut Down the Government, "Why We Say Republicans Are Giving Tax Breaks to Corporations and the Rich," summary of labor, health and human services, and education appropriations bill; fact sheets, "Keep Student Loans Affordable," "Johnston-Robb Regulatory Reform Threatens Job Safety Protections," "Service Contract Repeal Hurts Low-Wage Workers," "Davis-Bacon Act Protects Workers' Paychecks"; materials on worker safety and health, impact by state of proposed OSHA budget cuts; question and answer sheet re executive order re striker replacement; AARP fact sheet, "Just the Facts: Older Americans Already Pay Very High Out-of-Pocket Health Costs," with attached charts
- Upper Hudson Area Labor Council-Meeting 8/26/96, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  Minutes; flyers by National Council of Senior Citizens and AFL- CIO, supporting Rep. Maurice Hinchey, preserving Medicare, Medicaid; script and instruction sheet for "Labor to Neighbor," door-to-door effort to union households on behalf of endorsed candidates, by NYS AFL-CIO; schedule of labor programs sponsored by Cornell ILR
- NYS AFL-CIO Awards, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  Call for nominations for 1997 NYS AFL-CIO Community Service Awards; report from the AFL- CIO Elected Leader Task Force on Organizing, "Organizing for Change, Changing to Organize," with conference registration form; report of NYS AFL-CIO, "Restoring the Promise: The Reform of Workers' Compensation in New York State," with sheet summarizing recommendations, May 1997; materials re Labor to Neighbor door-to-door campaign; flyer for Rally for Justice at Western Beef
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1998-1999 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  School Board minutes
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 18)
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 19)
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 20)
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 21)
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 23)
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 24)
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 25)
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 26)
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 27)
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 28)
- Contract Negotiation Forms (Box 17, Folder 29)
  Contract analysis checklist and questionnaire re importance of points for negotiation
- Rhinecliff Teachers Association Improper Practice Charge n.d. (Box 17, Folder 30)
  Improper Practice Charge Brief on Behalf of Rhinecliff Teachers Association
- Rhinecliff Union Free School District, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  Staff meeting minutes; proposed policy re child abuse reporting; memos from superintendent re gang activity, other issues; memos from president of teachers association to principal re alleged violation of collective bargaining agreement, to superintendent re communications problems, Freedom of Information requests for job descriptions and salary information, other issues
- Bus Liability Forms, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  Teacher-Bus Driver Exemption of Liability forms
- Constitutions, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  Constitution of Rhinecliff Union Free School Teachers Association, March 1976; constitution as amended January 1992
- Funding Special Acts, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  Correspondence between NYSUT officers re funding of Special Act (institutional) schools
- Bonus Program, 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  Salary schedules for administrative and support personnel; Freedom of Information request for salary and bonus information, from vice president of Rhinecliff Teachers' Association
- Health Insurance, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  Memos from Dutchess Educational Health Insurance Consortium re premium rates and alternate benefit plan for 1992-93 and 1993-94; related materials
- Sick Bank Agreement, 1975-1993 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  Agreement between the district and the RTA (Rhinecliff Teachers Association), October 10, 1993; Improper Practice Charge for change in group sick leave bank before new contract was negotiated, 1992; memo re sick bank, 1975
- RTA Ballots, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  Ballots for teachers association officers
- Conference Compensation, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  Grievance and related correspondence re reimbursement for attendance at professional conference
- Committee Questionnaire (Box 17, Folder 40)
  List of standing and special committees on which teacher association members might serve
- RA Meeting-NYC, 1993-1996 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  Conference call for Pre-Representative Assembly Local Presidents' Conference, February 28-29, 1996; NYSUT Constitution, May 1993; proposed resolution, Funding for Special Act Public Schools for Handicapped and Neglected Children
- Proxy Ballot (Box 17, Folder 42)
  Blank proxy and absentee ballots for Rhinecliff Teachers' Association
- Rhinecliff-Ron Rosen, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  Letter to Rhinecliff schools superintendent Ron Rosen and school board re (mostly negative) evaluation by teachers of principal Lesley Hurd
- Sick Bank, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  Sick bank request from teacher to cover extension of maternity leave, May 19, 1984; sick bank request from same teacher after burn accident to cover disability period, September 11, 1984; ballots from members approving requests; minutes of Sick Bank Committee meeting; draft revision of sick leave bank bylaws, Monticello Teachers Association; letter to Rhinecliff superintendent objecting to stipulation of agreement re sick bank
- Board of Education, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  Letter to president of Rhinecliff Board of Education from president of Rhinecliff Teachers Association requesting that the faculty be included in the selection process for future appointments to the school board
- NYSUT General Info, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 46)
  NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office 1993-94 Survey of Stipends, Dues, and Release Time; NYSUT report, Median Teacher Salaries and Inflation: Special Act Districts, meeting of Special Act Districts, April 18, 1994; memo to teachers and aids from principal Leslie Hurd, requesting that time-off slip requests be submitted to her, and that no passes be issues to students during the first period, May 27, 1994
- Special Acts Info, 1992-1994 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  List of Special Act schools, with local presidents; publication re Special Act schools, with attached position paper on tuition methodology reform, by Coalition of Special Act School Districts; State Education Department letter re tuition rate-setting methodologies for students with disabilities, June 7, 1994
- Pius Contracts, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  Pius XII Youth and Family Services 1992 Annual Report; letter from Pius XII executive vice president and chief operating officer to interim superintendent of Rhinecliff Union Free School District with attached 1995-96 lease agreement, health services agreement, and operational services agreement, July 1, 1995; letter to Rhinecliff superintendent from Pius XII director of operation with attached agreements, July 1, 1992; spreadsheet re contracts (monthly payments of rent, utilities, etc.), 1989-90
- Rhinecliff Teachers Association, 1987-1988 (Box 17, Folder 49)
  Correspondence re salaries and distribution of additional funds; staff roster; stipulation of agreement
- RTA Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  Correspondence between teachers associations at various Special Act schools (West Park, Hopevale, George Junior Republic, Rhinecliff), requesting copies of their collective bargaining agreements; correspondence between Rhinecliff Teachers Association president, superintendent, and president of Board of Education re rental agreements, professional development
- RTA Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 51)
  Smoking Proposal Committee Report and related correspondence, 1990; memo to superintendent re health and safety issues (non-working toilet facilities, lack of potable water), need to request Village of Rhinebeck to perform utility maintenance during school vacation, October 24, 1990; letter explaining difficulties in changing the municipal flushing schedule, February 26, 1991; related correspondence; letter to superintendent re aggression reports, May 16, 1991; memo from NYSUT Regional Coordinator Jan Conti re Regents decision to increase class size at Special Act schools, March 27, 1991; rules for bus drivers; letter to district noting unanimous rejection of Employee Assistance Program by teachers association, n.d.
- RTA Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 52)
  NYSUT Survey of Local Presidents of Special Act Schools, with cover letter, February 4, 1992; list of state representatives (Senate and Assembly) for Special Act school districts; list of union officers for 1991-92; memo re dues structure for 1991-92; letter from superintendent re retirement incentive program; benefit comparison of Empire Plan with Dutchess Plan
- RTA Correspondence (folder 1), 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 53)
  Petition to Rhinecliff Union Free School Board of Education by members of Rhinecliff Teachers Association, decrying the "evasive charade" in months of negotiations and "insulting offer" in proposed contract, noting that they were "cursed at, spat upon, punched, bitten and harassed" by their students, October 27, 1992; five-page reply from district board, decrying teachers' "preoccupation with financial matters," November 13; 1992-93 Rhinecliff Teachers Association Proposed Annual Budget; other proposed contract terms; letter from vice president for program services, re decision to transition from a co-ed residential facility to one serving boys only, March 5, 1993; memos re sick bank, payroll schedule; letter from president of Board of Education to superintendent, outlining expectations for improvement in his management, including communication, responsiveness to faculty, and other areas, June 3, 1993
- RTA Correspondence (folder 2), 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 54)
  Pius XII Youth and Family Services report from the Office of the President, "The State of the Agency," September 1992; memo from Pius XII Youth and Family Services re Mission Statement Conference, with agenda, April 23, 1993; memo re lunch and hall duty, noting inadequate time for lunch, with schedule, October 5, 1993; letter to superintendent re discourteous behavior of principal, May 13, 1993; notice of alleged safety and health violation, filed by Rhinecliff Teachers Association and CSEA Units I and II with NYS Department of Labor, with cover letter to superintendent, January 26, 1993; letter of resignation from chair of Rules Committee "due to lack of professional courtesy from the administration," February 3, 1993; memo to staff re emergency treatment team and altercation between several students, January 5, 1993; five-page response from teachers' association to communication from Rhinecliff Board of Education of November 13, noting that it was "outraged by the Board's dishonesty," December 22, 1992; letter to superintendent from physical education department chair, expressing grave concern over roach infestation, November 3, 1992; memos re payroll schedule, reassignment of teaching assistant
- RTA Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 55)